

(a)

Professional Summary

Enthusiastic, self-starting, and dedicated software developer. Currently enrolled in an intensive Bootcamp at Coder Academy in Melbourne, building proficiency in front and backend programming languages and gaining experience in testing frameworks. Critical thinking and excellent problem-solving skills due to a background in business that helps to create MVPs that meet user and business requirements.



Education

2020-03 -2021-01 Diploma, Information Technology

Coder Academy - Melbourne

2019-07 -Current ISTQB Foundation Level Certification

ANZTB

2004-03 -2007-02 **Bachelors of Business Administration**

D.A.V. College - Amritsar(India)

1990-03 -2003-02 Holy Heart High School - Amritsar(India)



Projects Done

Project Name: FarmerSmartDescription:

- A two sided marketplace app built on Ruby on Rails framework as an assessment for term 2 at Coder Academy
- Website Link: https://secure-brook-35449.herokuapp.com/



Address

Melbourne, VIC, 3000

Phone

047 383 7804

E-mail

vipul.seth022@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/vipul-seth-a06730184/

WWW

https://github.com/vipul022



HTML5, CSS, JavaScript

React, React Testing Library,

Jest

MongoDB, ExpressJS, NodeJS

Ruby, Ruby on Rails

SQL, Postgres

Git, Github, Command Line

Visual Studio Code, Postman

Tools - Figma, Lucid chart, DB diagram

 Github Link: https://github.com/vipul022 /farmersmart-

Project Name: Portfolio Website

Description:

- Portfolio website created using HTML5 and CSS as an assessment for term 1 at Coder Academy
- Website Link: https://vipulseth.netlify.com/
- Github Link: https://github.com/vipul022/vipul022my-portfolio

Project Name: Weather or Not

Description:

- Website Link: https://www.jasonstacy.com.au/src/assets/weather or not/
- Github Link: https://github.com/vipul022 /hackathon
- Weather App built on Vanilla JavaScript using weatherbit api
- Participated in the JavaScript remote hackathon and peer programmed using the git forking workflow

Project Name: Express Chat

Description:

- Website Link: https://calmcrag-33201.herokuapp.com/
- Github Link: https://github.com/vipul022 /chat-app
- Real time chat application built using express server, socket.io and MongoDB database
- Used express-handlebars for front end
- Participated in the Express remote hackathon and peer programmed using the git forking workflow.



Work History

2016-12 -2020-02

Service Provider

UPS Pty Ltd, Melbourne, Victoria

- Completed on-time deliveries by choosing best and most efficient routes
- Conferred with dispatch to relay delays, receive route and adjust plans to meet daily targets
- Fostered positive working relationships with

customers by responding to questions and concerns

2015-08 -2016-11

Service Provider

Limitless Couriers, Melbourne, Victoria

- Coordinated efficient routes for optimal delivery scheduling and maximum daily performance
- Worked for various companies (DHL, Fastway, Couriers Please, UPS)

2009-11 -2015-01

Proprietor

Veekay Textiles, Amritsar, India

- Grew textiles business from ground up, including developing business plans, managing accounts and obtaining initial investments
- Developed and managed relationships with vendors and suppliers
- Traveled to various states of India in order to expand the business

2005-08 -2008-10

Co-Owner

Bhagwati Enterprises, Amritsar, Punjab

- Developed key operational initiatives to drive and maintain substantial business growth
- Managed purchasing, sales, marketing, and customer account operations of family owned cotton waste recycling factory
- Drove setting up of latest machinery to propel the business forward and adapt to market changes